(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ルル
作詞・作曲：テイカ-α
Lulu
Lyrics/Composition: Teika-alpha
かぜひくの
Catching a cold
お布団なくて寒い
It's cold without a futon
お布団はがされて寒い
It's cold with the futon stripped away
夜明けにあなたが来る
You come at dawn
あなたが笑っている
You are laughing
きっと僕には
Surely to me
見えないと思ってる
You think you're invisible
そっと手を伸ばして
Quietly reaching out a hand
いったい何をするつもり？
What on earth do you intend to do?
かぜひくの
Catching a cold
寝たふりをして過ごす
Pretending to be asleep
少しだけ暖かくなる
It gets a little warmer
隣であなたが眠る
You sleep beside me
うるさい寝言は無視して
Ignoring your noisy sleep-talking
ああ 昨日の夜ご飯
Ah, last night's dinner
何食べたか思い出せない
I can't remember what I ate
ああ いつも通りの朝
Ah, a morning like any other
どうか世界が滅びぬように
Praying the world doesn't end
かぜひいたって知らないの
I won't care if you catch a cold
お布団ないと寒い
It's cold without a futon
お布団隠されて寒い
It's cold with the futon hidden
震える指先たち
Trembling fingertips
吐息はストーブみたい
Breaths are like a stove
きっとすぐには
Surely not right away
起きないと思ってる
You think I won't wake up
ずっとそばで見てる
I'm watching from nearby all the time
いったい何をするつもり？
What on earth do you intend to do?
ふかふか
Soft and fluffy
ぜがひでも僕はたぬき
By all means, I'm a tanuki
伝わる温もりは過熱
The warmth felt is overheating
まるまる体ふたつ
Two round bodies
この際 悪夢は無視して
At this point, ignore the nightmares
寝たふりをして過ごす
Pretending to be asleep
少しだけ暖かくなる
It gets a little warmer
隣であなたが眠る
You sleep beside me
うるさい寝言は無視して
Ignoring your noisy sleep-talking
重なるおでこにキスして
Kissing my overlapping forehead
はーい！というわけで
Hi! And so,
月の上からハローボ！
Hello-bo from the top of the moon!
ロボ子の4周年記念ライブにみんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming to Roboco's 4th anniversary live!
あ、やばい 近づくとなんか星空が
Oh, no. When I get close, the starry sky...
ちょっと壁紙みたいになってんのがばっ…バレてしまう…
It'll be ex... exposed that it's like wallpaper...
まずいまずいまずい
Bad, bad, bad
でも見て！このロボ子の乗ってる月！
But look! This moon Roboco is on!
可愛いでしょう！
Cute, right!
うん！あ、もうすごい！一番星、輝く一番星にロボ子、なってしまった気分だよ！エヘヘヘ！
Yeah! Ah, it's amazing! I feel like I've become the first star, the shining first star! Ehehehe!
はい！というわけで、みんな今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Yes! So, everyone, thank you for coming today!
盛り上がっているかー！どうだー！
Are you hyped up! How is it!
ロボ子は座って盛り上がっています！本日はですね、えー...
Roboco is sitting and getting hyped! Today, well...
ロボ子4周年記念ライブのハッシュタグを使って、いっぱいツイートしてほしいんだよ！
I want you to tweet a lot using the hashtag for Roboco's 4th Anniversary Live!
可愛いロボ子をいっぱい、いっぱい撮ってほしいな！
I want you to take lots and lots of pictures of cute Roboco!
本日のライブはですね、なんと！ゲストもサムネで公開していっぱいいるんですけれども、歌もいっぱい歌うんですけれども、
Today's live, what! There are many guests as shown in the thumbnail, and I'll be singing many songs, but...
なんと！アップデートがチラチラチラチラとあるらしいということでね、
What! It seems there are some updates here and there,
何が一体アップデートされたのか、楽しみに見ててください！
Please look forward to seeing what exactly has been updated!
え、みんな何がアップデートされると思う？
Eh, what do you all think will be updated?
新衣装？新衣装？うふふ。ねー、そう。みんなちょっと考えといて。そう。
New outfit? New outfit? Ufufu. Right, that's it. Everyone, think about it for a bit. Yeah.
それを、このね、絶対なんとかだと思う、これなんとかじゃないのっていうのもね、ぜひこちらのタグで...
And, like "I definitely think it's this" or "Isn't it that", please use this tag...
ロボコ、トレンドを目指したいので、みんなツイートしてトレンドに乗せてくれ！頼んだぞ！
Roboco wants to trend, so everyone, tweet and get me on the trends! I'm counting on you!
え、可愛すぎ。え、この女、可愛すぎ。え、なんと今日で4周年記念ライブ？
Eh, too cute. Eh, this girl is too cute. Eh, and today is the 4th Anniversary Live?
可愛いでしょう！
Cute, right!
ね、初見の方も、常連のロボサーも、ロボ子のこといっぱい好きになってもらえるようにロボコ、ダンスも歌もいっぱい練習したので、
So that newcomers and regular Robosa alike can come to like me more, I practiced dancing and singing a lot,
楽しみに楽しみに最後まで1時間たっぷり楽しみに見ててください！
So look forward to it, and enjoy the full hour until the end!
噛むのはご愛嬌ということで！うふふ。
Stumbling over words is part of the charm! Ufufu.
ロボコ、ロボコだから許してほしいんだよ。あははは！
Because it's Roboco, I want you to forgive me. Ahahaha!
はい！というわけでね、早速なんか、ちょっと今ロボコは地上にいないんだけど、
Yes! So, without further ado, right now Roboco isn't on the ground,
あれ？なんかちょっと下の方から匂いがするから、ちょっと降りてみようかなって思ったけど、あれ？意外と月が...
Huh? I smell something from below, so I thought I'd go down, but... huh? Surprisingly, the moon is...
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
あれ？なんか、月ってこんなに身近な存在だったんですね。あはは！
Huh? It seems the moon was such a familiar presence. Ahahaha!
あれ？結構近い存在だったのかもしれない.降りちゃったじゃあ、月バイバイしよう。お月様！
Huh? It might have been quite close. I've landed, so let's say bye-bye to the moon. Mr. Moon!
戻れ！バイバーイ！
Go back! Bye-bye!
入らない。入らなかった。ちょっと後で魔法の呪文をかけるわ。うふふ。
It's not going in. It didn't go in. I'll cast a magic spell later. Ufufu.
というわけでですね、ちょっといい匂いがするから、あまりちょっと...ん？ふむふむ。
So, I smell something good, so... hm? I see, I see.
あ！ちょっとロボコ、向こうに何かいい香りがしそうなので、ちょっとみんな走ってくるよ！ちょっと待ってて！
Ah! I smell a nice scent over there, so Roboco's going to run over! Everyone, wait a bit!
よし、行くぞ！とりゃー！
Alright, here I go! Toryaaa!
カランコロン、カランコロン、カランコロン。お、なんだこの音。おー。
Clatter, clatter, clatter. Oh, what's this sound? Ohhh.
今日はなんか、ここのカフェでイベントやってるらしいよ。
It seems there's an event at this cafe today.
えー！カフェ？どう見てもステージなのだー、これ。
What! Cafe? No matter how you look at it, this is a stage.
え？なんか舞台だよね。なんか変だなー。え？
Eh? It's like a stage. Something's weird. Eh?
いらっしゃいませ。あれ？天使...え？何？
Welcome. Huh? Angel... eh? What?
もしかして、アンポンタンの方ですか？
By any chance, are you from Ampon-tan?
あ、ぽん、ポン...えー、ポンアンアンタンと...えー、ハロー、ロボ子です！
Ah, pon, pon... uh, Pon-An-An-Tan and... uh, hello, I'm Roboco!
違うでしょ！アンポンダンツの、アキ・ローゼンタール！そして！
That's wrong! Aki Rosenthal of Ampon-dance! And!
ポンタンとのロボ子です！
It's Roboco with Pontan!
何がポンしてんだ、こいつ！おい！そして！
What is she "pon-ing" about, this one! Hey! And!
そして、タンタンとの姫森ルーナなのだー！くそー、乗っ取れなかったー！
And Himemori Luna with Tan-tan! Damn, I couldn't take over!
何言ってんだよ、もう。いや、普段からね、高精度のポンをありがとうございます。
What are you saying already. Well, thank you for the usual high-precision "pon".
どなななよ。
What do you mean by that.
あら、ここ壁なんだろう？
Oh, is this a wall?
おいしいもの期待してたんだよ、こちらのルーナは。
Luna was expecting something delicious.
あ、まあ姫様用にパンケーキもね、こちら透明なパンケーキとなっております。
Ah, well, for the Princess, we have a pancake... a transparent pancake.
心が綺麗な人にしか見えませんと。
It can only be seen by those with a pure heart.
あー、おいしそう！
Ah, it looks delicious!
見えねえわ！
I can't see it!
おい！だめじゃないか！
Hey! That's no good!
あら、心がまだまだのご様子ですね。
My, it seems your heart isn't quite there yet.
まったく！で、どうなの？注文はここできんの？
Honestly! Anyway, can we order here?
うん、できるに決まってるじゃないですの。
Yes, of course you can.
あら！じゃあさ、ちょっとおなじみのメニューさ、頼みたいなーって思うんだけど、
Oh! In that case, I'd like to order the usual menu,
一緒にいいですか？言ってもらっても。
Would you mind saying it with me?
しょうがないな。ありありなのら。
I guess I have no choice. It's okay, nanora.
じゃあ、行きますよ。
Okay, here we go.
ご注文は？
What is your order?
せーの！
Ready, set...
ぼなぺてぃーと♡S！
Bon Appétit♡S!
歌をするぞ！
Let's start the song!
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Surprise!
Service!
We are Stile!
ぼなぺてぃーと♡S
作詞：こだまさおり　作曲：y0c1e
Bon Appétit♡S
Lyrics: Saori Kodama, Composition: y0c1e
さあ扉を開けて
Now, open the door
未知なるパラダイスへ体験しよう
and experience an unknown paradise
おいでおいでよ
Come on, come on
君を待つのは次のオアシス
what's waiting for you is the next oasis
ほっこり日常に　ちょっぴりスパイス
A little spice for your relaxing daily life
くるんくるん　かき混ぜちゃうんだ
Spinning, spinning, mixing it all up
くるんくるん　特製のフレーバー
Spinning, spinning, a special flavor
サービスサービス　ご褒美タイム
Service, service, reward time
おもてなし
Hospitality
心込めて
with all our heart
Welcome to wai　私たちと一緒に
Welcome to our... with us together
めくるめく　ワンダーデイリー
A dazzling wonder daily
愛情ましもし　ぼのぼのなでなで
More and more love, bono-bono, petting
誠心誠意　務めます (Yeah!)
I'll serve with all my heart (Yeah!)
君の元気チャージに　一役買えるかな
I wonder if I can help recharge your energy
恋への暗示も
Hints for love,
愛への感じも
and feelings for love,
意外と悪くないでしょ
aren't as bad as you'd think, right?
ぼのぼの　ブレン道スタイル
Bono-bono, Blend Style
君にキュンキュンキュン
My heart's throbbing for you
ハートにパンパンパン
My heart's pounding
ぼのぼの　ブレン道スタイル
Bono-bono, Blend Style
お口に合いましたか？
Was it to your liking?
お口に合うといいな
I hope it was to your liking
Bon Appétit
千客万来！
Customers pouring in!
いつもなんか不本意ながらも
Even though it's always somewhat involuntary,
いつだって需要は斜め上
the demand is always unexpected
そんじゃいっか　本当の私は
Well then, the real me is...
シークレットモードで営業スイッチ
switching to business on secret mode
くるんくるん　お待たせを
Spinning, spinning, sorry to keep you waiting
くるんくるん　秘密のフレーバー
Spinning, spinning, a secret flavor
サービスサービス　極上タイム
Service, service, premium time
癒しとは
This is how
斯くあるべき
healing should be
Welcome to wai　私たちのお店に
Welcome to our... in our shop
本日もようこそ
Welcome today too
待ち待ってた　至れり尽くせり
I've been waiting for this attentive service
第１の歓迎 (Yeah!)
The primary welcome (Yeah!)
君のお疲れ様に　ぴったりのレシピで
With a recipe perfect for your tiredness
こう言及かな
Is it like this mention?
ああいう言及かな
Or is it like that mention?
満足でもらえてるかな
I wonder if you're satisfied
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Smile!
Strange!
Serious!
Selfish!
Secret!
Super!
We are Stile!
さあ扉を開けて
Now, open the door
愉快なパラダイス　怖がらずにおいで
it's a pleasant paradise, don't be afraid and come
そういつも通りの毎日に　素敵な期待を込めたら
Yes, if you put wonderful expectations into your usual daily life
召し上がれ
Enjoy your meal
Welcome to wai　私たちと一緒に
Welcome to our... with us together
めくるめく　ワンダーデイリー
A dazzling wonder daily
愛情ましもし　ぼのぼのなでなで
More and more love, bono-bono, petting
誠心誠意　務めます (Yeah!)
I'll serve with all my heart (Yeah!)
君の元気チャージに　一役買えるかな
I wonder if I can help recharge your energy
恋への暗示も
Hints for love,
愛への感じも
and feelings for love,
意外と悪くないでしょ
aren't as bad as you'd think, right?
ぼのぼの　ブレン道スタイル
Bono-bono, Blend Style
君にキュンキュンキュン
My heart's throbbing for you
ハートにパンパンパン
My heart's pounding
ほな　ほな　ほな　プロデュースたい！
Hona, hona, hona, it's time to produce!
ぼっちに会いますか？
Will you meet me all alone?
おなもに聞かせてね
Let me hear your "Onamo."
どっちに合うといいな
I hope it fits one way or another.
はるか遠い遠い昔　巻かれた首輪
A collar put on long, long ago.
人が欲しい　人が欲しいと叫ぶ　呪いの首輪
A cursed collar that screams, "I want people, I want people."
怒らないで　見捨てないで　どこもいかないで
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere.
強く絞める　吐くまで絞める　人がいないいないと
Tighten it hard, tighten 'til I gag, when there's no one, no one around.
いい成績でしょう　ねえ　ねえ
I have good grades, don't I? Hey, hey.
いい子でしょう
I'm a good girl, aren't I?
かわいい子でしょう　ねえ　ねえ
I'm a cute girl, aren't I? Hey, hey.
いい子でしょう
I'm a good girl, aren't I?
苦しいねえ
It hurts, doesn't it?
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me.
もっともっと愛して
Love me more and more.
愛して　愛して
Love me, love me.
狂おしいほどに
So much that it's maddening.
苦しい　苦しい
It hurts, it hurts.
呪縛を解いて解いてね
Undo the curse, undo it, please.
止められない　ああ
It can't be stopped, ah.
身体　身体　大きくなって　も小さい首輪
No matter how big my body gets, the collar is still small.
苦しくなる　足りなくなる　人が人が足りない
It starts to hurt, it's not enough, people, people are not enough.
クラスの誰にも負けない　綺麗な子でしょう
I'm a beautiful girl, better than anyone in class, right?
ねえ　あの子よりも　どの子よりも　誰も彼も私を見てよ
Hey, better than that girl, better than any girl, everyone, look at me.
体育館裏　あなたに告白を
Behind the gym, I'll confess to you.
嘘みたいでしょう
It seems like a lie, doesn't it?
あなたが好きなの
I love you.
汚いくらいにあなたを
To a degree that's almost filthy, I...
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me.
全部あげる　あなたに
I'll give you everything.
あなたに全部背負ってもらうよ
I'll have you bear everything for me.
足りない　あなたが
It's not enough, you are...
足りない　離さないよ
...not enough, I won't let go.
ああ　ごめんなさい
Ah, I'm sorry.
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me.
もっともっと愛して
Love me more and more.
愛して　愛して
Love me, love me.
狂おしいほどに
So much that it's maddening.
苦しい　離さない
It hurts, I won't let go.
苦しい　もっともっとね
It hurts, more and more, okay?
幸せなの　ああ
I'm so happy, ah.
Oh my god.
愛のネタバレ別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, looks like a breakup.
人生のネタバレ死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, looks like death.
なにそれ 意味深でかっこいいじゃん
What's that? So meaningful and cool, right?
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ、しけ
You're dancing with a glossary of that stuff, how lame.
神っぽいな
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
God-ish
Lyrics & Composition: PinocchioP
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Looks like it, looks like it.
神っぽいな
You're so God-ish.
猛威ぜ 猛威ぜ それ 猛威ぜ 猛威ぜ
Rampant, rampant, that's rampant, rampant.
逆に昂ぶってきたな
On the contrary, I'm getting pumped.
起きろ 起きろ 夢 起きろ 起きろ
Wake up, wake up, dream, wake up, wake up.
景気いいけど自業自得
Business is booming, but it's your own fault.
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
You're so God-ish, that's cheating. God-ish, that.
「I want you」「I want you」 IQが下がっていく感じ
"I want you," "I want you," feels like my IQ is dropping.
邪心っぽいな それ 卑怯 邪心っぽいな それ
You're so wicked-ish, that's cheating. Wicked-ish, that.
「I hate you」「I hate you」 害鳥はどっち
"I hate you," "I hate you," which one is the pest bird?
その髪型 その目 その口元
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth...
その香水 その服 そのメイク
That perfume, those clothes, that makeup...
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯 アレっぽいな それ
It looks like *that*, that's cheating. Looks like that.
その名言 その意見 その批評
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism...
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ
You're so God-ish, that's cheating. Admiring that style.
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Looks like it, looks like it.
神っぽいな
You're so God-ish.
メタ思考する本質は悪意
The essence of meta-thinking is malice.
人を小馬鹿にしたような作意
An intention to look down on others.
無難に生き延びるのは難しい
Surviving safely is difficult.
権力に飲まれてユラユラ キャリィ
Swallowed by power, swaying and carrying.
神を否定し神に成り代わり
Denying God and taking His place.
玉座で表明する小物たち
Small-timers expressing themselves on the throne.
批判に見せかけ自己愛のノリ、っていうの？
A vibe of self-love disguised as criticism, you know?
何言ってんの それ ウザい
What are you talking about? That's annoying.
何言ってんの それ
What are you talking about?
意味がよくわかんないし 眠っちゃうよ マジ
I don't really get it, and I'm seriously falling asleep.
飽きっぽいな おけ みんな 飽きっぽいな おけ
You're so fickle, okay, everyone's so fickle, okay.
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Give me something to dance to, give me a beam.
気色いね 気色いね それ 気色いね 気色いね
It's creepy, it's creepy, that's creepy, creepy.
逆にファンになってきたじゃん
On the contrary, I'm becoming a fan.
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器 ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね
It's small, it's small, your capacity is so small.
天才ゆえ孤独ですね 滑稽 滑稽
Loneliness because of genius, how comical, how comical.
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
You're so God-ish, that's cheating. God-ish, that.
執念 執念 違反で くたばっていく感じ
A feeling of dropping dead from obsession and violations.
焼けっぽいな それ 卑怯 焼けっぽいな それ
It looks burnt, that's cheating. Burnt-ish, that.
もう哀愁 哀愁 100万度の火
Already sorrow, sorrow, a million-degree fire.
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー
That title, those graphics, that story...
その温度 その歌 そのメロディ
That temperature, that song, that melody...
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯 アレっぽいな それ
It looks like *that*, that's cheating. Looks like that.
その名言 その意見 その批評
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism...
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ
You're so God-ish, that's cheating. Admiring that style.
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Looks like it, looks like it.
神っぽいな
You're so God-ish.
愛のネタバレ別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, looks like a breakup.
人生のネタバレ死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, looks like death.
すべて理解して 煩った
I understood everything and fell ill.
無邪気に踊っていたかった 人生
A life where I wanted to dance innocently.
この世で造花より 綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, no flower is more beautiful than an artificial one.
何故ならばすべては 嘘でできている アンチパシー
Because everything is made of lies. Antipathy.
フォニイ
作詞・作曲：ツミキ
Phony
Lyrics & Composition: Tsumiki
絶望の雨は あたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pokes through my umbrella.
湿らす前髪と 心の襞 煩わしい
Dampened bangs and heart's folds, how troublesome.
いつしか言の葉は 有り体に切って
Eventually, the leaves of words were bluntly cut off.
事の実があたし熟れている
The fruit of things is ripening within me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて 自らを失ったメイク
Reflecting in the mirror, drawing lies, makeup that lost its self.
パッパッパラッパッパッパラ なぜなぜ 数えて遊びましょ
Pa-pa-para, why, why, let's play by counting.
タッタッタラッタッタッタラ なぜなぜ ここで踊るのでしょう
Ta-ta-tara, why, why, I wonder why I'm dancing here.
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things, what was I again?
それすら夜の手に 綻びて 愛のフォニイ
Even that unravels in the hands of the night, phony of love.
さよなら 窓辺には 戻らないで
Goodbye, don't return to the windowsill.
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ アンチパシー
Phony, phony, phony, tangled in lies, I am a phony. Antipathy.
鏡合わせに有体（ありてい）あって
Facing the mirror, being ordinary
色の眼があなたと射（い）ている
Colored eyes are shooting at you
鏡に映る私を欠いて
Lacking the me reflected in the mirror
誰しもが見間違い合って
Everyone misunderstanding each other
どうして愛なんてものに群がり
Why do they flock to something like love?
それを欲して生きるの
And live while craving it?
今日も泳いでる夜の泥（でい）が
Today too, the mud of the night is swimming
通り過ぎていく 踊り明かせよ
Passing by, dance the night away
パッパッパッパッパッパッパッナ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-na
嘘を吐いて歌いましょう
Let's tell lies and sing
タッタッタッタッタッタッタッタナ
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-na
何故ここが痛むのでしょう
Why does it hurt here?
散々な日々は変わらないわ
The terrible days won't change
絶望の羽目は止まないわ
The plight of despair won't stop
サヨナラも言える間もないわ
There's no time even to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, Phony, Phony
嘘に絡まっている 只（ただ）
Just entangled in lies
簡単なことも分からないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の手に解（ほだ）されて
Even that is bound by the hand of the night
愛のように
Like love
サヨナラ またねと呟いた
I muttered, "Goodbye, see you later"
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, Phony, Phony
嘘に絡まっているあたしは
I, entangled in lies, am
フォニイ
Phony
造花だけが知っている秘密のフォニイ
A secret Phony known only to artificial flowers
「フォニイ」お送りいたしました！
I just performed "Phony"!
えーみんな、どう？かっこよかった？かわいかった？
Hey everyone, how was it? Was it cool? Was it cute?
え、どうかな？
Eh, what do you think?
あ、かっこよかった？嬉しい！
Oh, it was cool? I'm so happy!
え、そうなの。今回ね、ステージのね、
Yeah, that's right. For this stage...
このかっこいい映像と共にお願いいたしました。
I asked for these cool visuals.
そしてね、ダンスもめちゃめちゃかっこよかったでしょ？これ。
And the dance was super cool too, right?
めちゃめちゃ難しかった！
It was extremely difficult!
そうなの。あ、あれ？みんな、もしかして、
Yeah. Oh, wait. Everyone, by any chance...
さっきもチラチラコメント見えたけど、
I saw glimpses of comments earlier, but...
新しいものに気づいちゃいましたかね？
did you notice something new?
そうなんですよ。ロボ子の頭をご覧ください。
That's it. Please look at Roboco's head.
こちら、狐のお面、おニューでございます！
This fox mask here is brand new!
え、どうこれ？ロボコのこの衣装に似合うんじゃないの？
How is it? Doesn't it go well with Roboco's outfit?
あらあら、あらあらあら。
My, my. My oh my.
とってもミステリアスな感じになってしまったのかしらね。
I wonder if it's given me a very mysterious vibe.
みんな、いっぱいほら、カメラさんも寄って、
Everyone, come on, camera-san, get closer.
スクショいっぱい撮ってほしい。初お披露目だからね！
I want you to take lots of screenshots. It's the first reveal!
どう、可愛いでしょ。コンコン。
It's cute, right? Kon-kon.
コンコン。
Kon-kon.
コンコンポーズも取ってしまって。
I even did the "kon-kon" pose.
そうなんですよ。ぜひね、このスクショもみんな撮ってくれたら、
Exactly. If you all take these screenshots...
ハッシュタグ、ロボ子4周年記念ライブで呟いていってください。
please tweet them with the hashtag #ロボ子4周年記念LIVE.
この可愛さをみんな広めていけー！頼むぞ！
Spread this cuteness to everyone! I'm counting on you!
あ、チャンネル登録・高評価してないやつは、
Ah, and anyone who hasn't subscribed or liked yet...
いないよね？まさか。
there isn't anyone like that, right? Surely not.
さてね、かっこいい曲が続いたわけなんですけれども。
Now then, we've had a series of cool songs.
ロボ子、実はもうちょいかっこいい曲歌いたいなーと思ってて。
Actually, Roboco wants to sing an even cooler song.
どうやら別ステージで、
It seems like on another stage...
凄くかっこいい女たちの匂いがするから、コンコン。
I can smell some very cool women. Kon-kon.
あっちかな？ちょっと今、狐のお面付けてるからかもしんないけど。
Maybe over there? It might be because of the fox mask...
嗅覚が…コンコン。匂いますね。これ、あ、匂いますね。
but my sense of smell... kon-kon. I definitely smell something.
じゃあちょっと向こうに大ジャンプしてみようかな。
So, I think I'll try taking a big jump over there.
それでは行くぞ！せーの、ジャンプ！
Here I go! One, two, jump!
Ha, We are Chuoh! / My 片手に分からす忠告
Ha, We are Chuoh! / Giving advice they'll understand with my one hand
Uh, check it out, We are Chuoh!
Check it out, we are 言の葉党
Check it out, we are the Kotonoha Party
堂々と取り出す 言（こと）と言葉を
Dignifiedly bringing out things and words
侍らす そこどけ男共
Keep them around, step aside, men
残念ながら 某（それがし）こちら党派
Unfortunately, I belong to this faction
乙統女（おとめ）の 意のままに進む
Proceeding as Otome wills
OK? 媚（こ）びずにつける ケリ
OK? Settling it without flattery
御覧遊ばせ
Behold
これが私のマニフェスト パーティー
This is my manifesto party
頭が高いですね 敵にもならない
You're acting high and mighty, you're not even a threat
噛みつくのなし いらないビーフ
No biting, I don't need any beef
気安く呼んでんじゃないわ 一時（いちじ）
Don't call me so familiarly, Ichijiku
Bad Queens の罠にはまれ
Fall into the trap of the Bad Queens
上がるしかない 支持率
The approval rating has nowhere to go but up
リップカラーを今固め
Fixing my lip color now
ほら正しくにらみ殺す 定め
Look, it's my destiny to glare you to death
不穏　ほとける名前
Ominous, melting name
勘解由小路　挙げろ脳漿その証
Kadenokouji, raise your brains as proof
Shut up, shut up, そんなんじゃダメ
Shut up, shut up, that won't do
生ぬるい仮文　言葉じゃ飛べないでしょう
Lukewarm borrowings, words won't let you fly, right?
碧　黄泉路にもREST IN PEACE
Blue, even on the road to Hades, rest in peace
無駄でしょ　葉っぱも結構　あてがわれる座礼と
It's useless, leaves are fine, and the seated bow you're given
私がネーム　これがマスターピース
強さは言の葉に宿すのよオールライト
I'm the name, this is the masterpiece
I'll lodge strength in words, alright
右左へ　さあ堂々進め　我らがルール
To the right and left, now proceed grandly, we are the rule
革命の章　最後に笑うのは乙女
The chapter of revolution, the one who laughs last is the maiden
西東へ　さあ頂上目指せ　我らがルール
To the west and east, now aim for the top, we are the rule
革命の章　もっと試したい　おんのれ
The chapter of revolution, I want to try more, damn you
Yeah, we are Chuo 舞い片手には分からす中指
Yeah, we are Chuo, dancing with one hand, showing the middle finger
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we are Chuo check it out 4-3-2-1 BANG!
手前、示せのよワンバース
You, show me your one verse
限界で蔓延るボーナス
A bonus spreading at the limit
あげてくれよクソ下手な展開の現在に引導を起きてよwake up
Give it to me, a death sentence for this shitty development, wake up
Hands up Hands up 今更即神仏レンジャー
Hands up, hands up, a ranger who's a living Buddha now
お遊戯から定番で鉄板
取りまとめるビート上から降りるディストーション
From playtime to standard to staple
A distortion descending from above the beat I manage
決めるターゲット　次は誰
Deciding the target, who's next?
ヒプノシス　クラクラさせてく言の葉アンセム
Hypnosis, making you dizzy, the Anthem of Words
切り拓く未来　乗りこなすフロー
The future I carve out, the flow I master
お手本の2人に任せ
Leave it to these two examples
並フロー見た黒白　素人真似事暴露
Seeing an average flow, black and white, exposing amateur imitations
躾の行き届いたこのメロ　次の情け売りです。でさあ行こう
This well-disciplined melody, selling mercy next. Now let's go
右左へ　さあ堂々進め　我らがルール
To the right and left, now proceed grandly, we are the rule
革命の章　最後に笑うのは乙女
The chapter of revolution, the one who laughs last is the maiden
西東へ　さあ頂上目指せ　我らがルール
To the west and east, now aim for the top, we are the rule
革命の章　もっと試したい　おんのれ
The chapter of revolution, I want to try more, damn you
応答せよ　応答せよ　さあ満たす生き様の情報戦
Respond, respond, now fulfill the information warfare of life
応答せよ　3人寄れば立ちまち喧し攻防戦
Respond, when three of us gather, it's instantly a noisy battle
掃討せよ　断るがうるさいを切り刻め
oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah
Sweep them away, I refuse, but cut up the noisiness
鳴らせな　革命の時間だ
Let it ring, it's the time of revolution
Yeah, we are Chuo 舞い片手には分からす中指
Yeah, we are Chuo, dancing with one hand, showing the middle finger
Yeah, we are Chuo check it out we are 言の葉党
Yeah, we are Chuo, check it out, we are the Party of Words
Color, we are Chuo ぺん走らすとっくに中毒
Color, we are Chuo, making the pen run, already addicted
Yeah, we are Chuo check it out we are 言の葉党
Yeah, we are Chuo, check it out, we are the Party of Words
研ぎ澄ますキレの技一つ
A single sharpened, sharp technique
空を描けば無双だし
If I paint the sky, I'm unparalleled
ほら見ろ他と違うテク
Look, a technique different from others
我らの品格もこれだ　check it out we are 言の葉党
This is our dignity too, check it out, we are the Party of Words
うわー！猫耳しっぽ！猫耳しっぽ！
Wow! Cat ears and tail! Cat ears and tail!
にゃんにゃん！
Meow meow!
え、かわいい！にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！
Oh, cute! Meow meow meow meow!
かっこいい2人のところに来たはずなんだけど...あれ？
I was supposed to come to where the two cool people are... wait?
ようこそ、いらっしゃいませ。
Welcome, glad to have you.
こんにちは、星街すいせいです。
Hello, I'm Hoshimachi Suisei.
猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu.
かっこいい2人で、やっぱりさっきの革命だよね。
うわー！猫耳しっぽ猫耳しっぽ！
You two are so cool, it really was a revolution just now.
Wow! Cat ears and tail, cat ears and tail!
にゃんにゃん！
Meow meow!
かわいい！
So cute!
猫耳しっぽゆらゆらにゃんにゃんにゃん！
Cat ears and tail swaying, meow meow meow!
どうやら4周年のようですね。
It seems to be your 4th anniversary.
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
あれ？あれ？あれ？ちょっと何かロボ子の夢かもしれないから
Huh? Huh? Huh? Since this might just be Roboco's dream...
ほっぺ引っ張ってもらってもいいかな？
...could you pull my cheek?
ぶー、痛い！
Ouch, it hurts!
4年間、よく頑張りました。
You've worked hard for these four years.
頑張りましたね。
You really did well.
ありがとうございます。やっぱりかっこいい2人で嬉しいな！
やめろ！
Thank you very much. I'm so happy because you two are so cool!
Stop it!
猫耳しっぽにゃんにゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！かわいいー！
Cat ears and tail meow meow meow meow meow! So cute!
うわー！にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！
Wow! Meow meow meow meow!
か、可愛いかもしれない。
Sh-She might be cute.
可愛いよ。
She is cute.
あなたもどうぞ、どうぞ。
You too, go ahead.
わー！猫耳しっぽかわいいよ！かわいいかわいいかわいいかわいい！
Wow! Cat ears and tail are so cute! Cute cute cute cute!
うわー！にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！
Wow! Meow meow meow meow!
猫耳！猫耳！
Cat ears! Cat ears!
猫耳はダメです。猫耳はダメですよ。
Cat ears are a no-go. You can't have cat ears.
あれ？猫耳はダメなんだ？
Oh? Cat ears are not allowed?
猫耳はダメですよ。そうなんだ。猫耳はダメらしい。
Cat ears are a no-go. I see. Apparently cat ears are not allowed.
4周年で一緒にカッコいい曲を歌ってくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you for singing such a cool song with me for my 4th anniversary.
いいえ。
Not at all.
どういたしまして。
You're very welcome.
呼んでくれてありがとう。
Thanks for inviting us.
ありがとうございます。なんと、お揃いの帽子あるんですね、僕たち。
Thank you. Oh, we have matching hats, don't we?
そう。可愛い。
Yes. They're cute.
かっこいい。
They're cool.
素敵。
They're lovely.
素晴らしい。
They're wonderful.
素敵かっこいい、とても似合っているわ。
Lovely and cool, they suit you very well.
はい。ありがとう。
Yes. Thank you.
もうラップに全力を使い果たして、MCを喋る頭はもうありません。
I've exhausted all my energy on the rap, so I've no brain power left to speak for the MC.
もう分かりません。何を言ったらいいのかしら。
I don't know anymore. I wonder what I should say.
その帽子に脳を詰めることを忘れてしまったわ。
I forgot to pack my brains into this hat.
脳？空っぽ？
Brains? Empty?
うにょーん！空っぽだー！かわいいー！そんなー！うほほーい！
Unyoon! They're empty! So cute! No way! Uhohooi!
かっこいいー！かっこいい椅子に座ってるじゃないか、星街！
So cool! You're sitting in a cool chair, aren't you, Hoshimachi!
そうです。
That's right.
似合ってるな おまえ。
It suits you.
自前です。
It's my own.
これ自前？
This is your own?
自前？
Her own?
おかしい、今日ロボ子...
That's strange, today Roboco...
チョコ先生に予約をしたんだけど...
...made a reservation with Choco-sensei, but...
大変高かったです。
It was very expensive.
見てるかもしれない、チョコ先生もね。うおー！
Choco-sensei might be watching too! Whoa!
チョコ先生、こちらの椅子、大変高かったです。
Choco-sensei, this chair was very expensive.
星街が座ると、ちょっとね、おこちゃまっぽくなっちゃうね。
When Hoshimachi sits in it, she looks a bit like a child, doesn't she?
たしかに。
True.
なんで！そんなことない！
Why?! That's not true!
だからこんなに今日おこちゃま彗星なのか。
So that's why we have Okosama-Suisei here today.
おこちゃま彗星。
Okosama-Suisei.
違う、違う、違う！取ったら誰よりも背が高いからね！
No, no, no! If I take this off, I'm taller than anyone!
一番ちっちゃいんじゃないの？
Isn't she the smallest?
そんな！え！そんな！そんな！そんな！
No way! Hey! No way! No way! No way!
すいちゃん、おかゆが意外と背が高い。
Sui-chan, Okayu is surprisingly tall.
ちょっと私も今、びっくりしました。
I was actually surprised by that just now, too.
おかゆちゃんに負けたー！
I lost to Okayu-chan!
残念でした。
Too bad.
どうやら次は、可愛い子が待っているらしいですけど。
It seems the next cute person is waiting.
え？あ、うさぎの子かしら。
Eh? Oh, a rabbit girl, I wonder?
もうそんな時間？やばい。
Is it that time already? Oh no.
じゃあロボ子ちょっとこの帽子脱ぎ捨てて、可愛い格好しなくちゃ！
Roboco has to take off this hat and get into a cute outfit!
頑張って、おくるんだます。
Good luck, Okurun-damasu.
おまえ、迷子すぎるだろ。どうなってんだこれ！
You're too lost! What's going on with this?!
難しいんだよ！
It's difficult!
じゃあロボ子行ってくるからね！またね！
Well, Roboco's going now! See you later!
いってらっしゃーい！バイバーイ！
Have a good trip! Bye bye!
ロマンスの不祥事に逃がさない
No escape from a romance scandal
消してあげる
I'll erase it for you
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
Sil-v-President
先生！私が大統領になったら、
Sensei! If I were to become president,
他の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします！
I'd exile any woman who flirts with other men!
先生！僕が大統領になったら、
Sensei! If I were to become president,
「ただの友達だよ」ってごまかす奴は、ヘドロにぶち込んで固めます！
I'd dump anyone who says "We're just friends" into sludge and solidify them!
宣戦布告だ！
It's a declaration of war!
先生、エモーショナル・クロニクル
Sensei, emotional chronicle
とめどない、溢れ出てくる
Incessant, overflowing
ギブミー・サジェスチョン
Give me suggestion
大嫌い、しょうがない
I hate it, can't be helped
屑は病気ね、バイバイバイ
Scum is a disease, bye bye bye
刑事、検察、陪審員、全部アタシで
Detective, prosecutor, jury, I'm all of them
さばき、裁き、裁きたい
Judge, judge, I want to judge
でしょ？ワン・ツー・スリー
Right? One, two, three
だだだ大統領になったらね
If I-I-I become president
まずは君を捕まえるね
First, I'll catch you
濡れたタオルで
With a wet towel
洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything
誰ですか？あの女
Who is she? That woman
本気ですか？そうですか
Are you serious? Is that so
ロマンスの不祥事に逃がさない
No escape from a romance scandal
消してあげる
I'll erase it for you
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
Sil-v-President
先生！僕が大統領になったら、
Sensei! If I were to become president,
「ただの仕事の付き合いだよ」って言う奴は、二度と働けなくしてやります！
I'll make sure anyone who says "It's just for work" never works again!
先生！光汰くん！
Sensei! Kota-kun!
「いや向こうが強引でさ」って言う男の口には、レジンを流し込んで固めてやります！
I'll pour resin into the mouths of men who say "They were forceful" and solidify them!
宣戦布告だ！
It's a declaration of war!
先生、ド派手・バッシング
Sensei, flashy bashing
マ・マ・まった、ガタガタ解消
W-w-wait, resolution of instability
刺すようなスクープで
With a piercing scoop
愛はない、理由じゃない
There's no love, it's not a reason
悪くないのにハイハイハイ
Even though I'm not wrong, yes yes yes
令状、同行、事情聴取、全部アタシで
Warrant, escort, questioning, I'm all of them
さばき、裁き、裁きたい
Judge, judge, I want to judge
でしょ？ワン・ツー・スリー
Right? One, two, three
だだだ大統領になってもね
Even if I become p-p-president
多分君は変わらないね
You probably won't change
白を切って
Playing innocent
のらりくらり交わすのね
Dodging and weaving evasively
どこですか？今アンタ
Where are you? Right now
見えちゃった？バレちゃった
Saw you? Got caught
ロマンスは不注意に微熱持ち
Romance carelessly carries a slight fever
消してしまいたい
I want to erase it
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, two, three
だだだ大統領になったらね
If I-I-I become president
マジで君を捕まえるね
I'll seriously catch you
濡れたタオルで
With a wet towel
洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything
どこですか？今アンタ
Where are you? Right now
見えちゃった？バレちゃった
Saw you? Got caught
用心にはご用心、さよなら
Beware of precautions, goodbye
代わりに銃声を
A gunshot instead
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
Sil-v-President
ロボ子先輩、4周年おめぺこー！
Roboco-senpai, 4th anniversary, congrats-peko!
ありがぺこー！ありがぺこー！ありがぺこー！
Arigato-peko! Arigato-peko! Arigato-peko!
いや一緒に「シル・ヴ・プレジデント」歌えてめちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！
I'm so happy to be able to sing 'Sil-v-President' together!
はじめましてぺこ！
Nice to meet you-peko!
よろぼこ！めっちゃ嬉しいよ！
Yoro-boko! I'm so happy!
や、楽し…あ、あれ？ていうか、え？
Yeah, fun... oh, wait? Actually, huh?
今更ながら気づいたぺこだけど、あれ？
I just realized it now, but wait?
ぺこらとロボ子先輩、あ、うさ耳…あれ？
Pekora and Roboco-senpai, ah, bunny ears... wait?
お揃いぺこじゃないですか！
We're matching-peko!
そうなんだよ、ぺこら！
That's right, Pekora!
もしやぺこランドに来るために
Does this mean just to come to Pekoland
うさ耳を生やしてくれたという事ぺこですな？
you grew bunny ears-peko?
いや、全然それ関係ないんだけど…
No, it has nothing to do with that...
あ、ちげぺこなの？ちげ…
Oh, really-peko? Really...
うん、全然関係ない、たまたまなんだけど…
Yeah, totally unrelated, it's just a coincidence...
でも、ロボ子はこの「シル・ヴ・プレジデント」をぺこらと歌いたくて…
But, Roboco wanted to sing 'Sylvie President' with Pekora...
え、本当ぺこ？
Eh, really-peko?
で、このダンスがロボ子実はお気に入りで…
And, Roboco actually really likes this dance...
わかりますよ、サビのところじゃないぺこですか？
I get it, you mean the chorus part-peko?
え、めちゃめちゃわかるじゃん！
Eh, you totally get it!
あ、じゃ、一緒にじゃこの「こうだよね」ってやつやります？
Ah, then, shall we do that 'it's like this' part together?
いいよ！いくよ！
Sure! Here we go!
せーの！
One, two!
ここ、ここ…あ…
Here, here... ah...
あれ？ほ？ん？
Huh? What? Hmm?
待って、ちょっと、ロボ子先輩それサビ前ぺこじゃないですか！
Wait, Roboco-senpai, that's before the chorus-peko!
え？え？な…
Eh? Eh? Wha...
な…踊りすぎて…サビ前って言ってるんですぺこじゃないですか！
You danced too much... I told you it's before the chorus-peko!
でもここ好きなんだもん！
But I like this part!
わかりますぺこですけど、もうちょっとしっかりしてくださいぺこです先輩！
I understand-peko, but please get it together-peko, senpai!
うん…それほどでも…
Yeah... not really...
それ褒めてないぺこだよ！
I wasn't praising you-peko!
や、でも、本当に踊りたくて、で、せっかくだったらロボ子とぺこらで…
But, I really wanted to dance, and since we're at it, I wanted Roboco and Pekora...
ちょっと反対の対象カラーで、同じうさ耳にしたかったなって思って！
to have matching bunny ears in contrasting colors!
あ、嬉しいぺこ嬉しいぺこ！
Ah, I'm so happy-peko, so happy-peko!
え、どうみんな？これ可愛い？どう？可愛い？可愛いでしょう！
Eh, what do you all think? Is this cute? Cute, right!
可愛いぺこじゃない？
Isn't it cute-peko?
可愛いぺこ！なんかポーズとるぺこ？ポーズなんか…
It's cute-peko! Shall we take a pose-peko? Like a pose...
なんか、ちょっとうさぎっぽいポーズ教えてよ！
Hey, teach me some rabbit-like pose!
うさぎっぽいポーズ教えてって…ロボ子先輩、うさぎはわかりやすいぺこでしょう流石に！
Teach you a rabbit-like pose... Roboco-senpai, a rabbit is easy to understand, surely!
ぴょんぴょんぴょん！
Pyon pyon pyon!
たくさん撮ってぺこ！可愛い可愛い！
Take lots of photos-peko! Cute, cute!
じゃ、みんなね、もう近づいていっぱいスクショ撮っておくれよな！
Then, everyone, please come closer and take lots of screenshots!
やらぺこ…いや、ぺこらとロボ子先輩と二人きりってなかなかないぺこじゃないですか？
Oh my-peko... isn't it quite rare for Pekora and Roboco-senpai to be alone together?
え、本当に珍しい！
Eh, it really is rare!
え、そうぺこですよね！
Eh, that's right-peko!
だから今日誘った時、すごくドキドキしてた！
That's why when I invited you today, my heart was pounding!
え！な…
Eh! Wha...
ぺこらも嬉しかったぺこですけどね、ロボ子先輩から誘われた時！
Pekora was also happy-peko, when I was invited by Roboco-senpai!
本当？
Really?
しかもぺこらこの「シル・ヴ・プレジデント」めちゃめちゃ好きぺこだったから、本当に嬉しかったぺこ！
And I really liked 'Sylvie President'-peko, so I was really happy-peko!
確かにそれ言ってたわ！
You certainly said that!
うん、だから、「やる」ってきて、嬉しかった！
Yeah, so when you said 'I'll do it', I was happy!
や、記念になったぺこ！ぺこらもね、でも本当に…
Yeah, it's become a great memory! For Pekora too, but really...
え、ね、ぺこら、ちょっと横向いてみてよ！ロボ子も一緒に横向くからさ！
Eh, hey, Pekora, try looking sideways! I'll look sideways too!
え？なんでぺこ？いいけど…
Eh? Why-peko? Okay, but...
えっと、カメラマンさん、近くに…あ、近くに言われなくても分かったみたいだ！
Um, Mr. Cameraman, please come closer... ah, he understood without being told!
おい！ロボ子先輩！
Hey! Roboco-senpai!
え、何何何？おめでとうの日だからって言って
Eh, what what what? Just because it's a celebration day,
いい事と悪い事があるぺこだろう！格差があると言いたいぺこなんでしょう！
there are things you should and shouldn't say-peko! You want to say there's a size difference-peko!
え、何も言ってないけどな！
Eh, I didn't say anything though!
これでもぺこらまだある方なんだぞ！
Even so, Pekora still has some, you know!
や、確かに、あった気がするけど、ロボ子の方が…
Well, certainly, I feel like you had some, but Roboco has...
や、ロボ子先輩はもうボン・キュ・ボンじゃないですか！
No, Roboco-senpai, you're just curvy, aren't you!
なんでロボットのくせに胸がこんなにあるぺこなの！？
Why do you have so much chest as a robot-peko!?
ロボットだからいっぱいあるんだよ！
It's because I'm a robot that I have plenty!
あるうことぺこな！悔しい！でも本当にね…
I see-peko! How frustrating! But really...
4周年おめでとうございますぺこです！
happy 4th anniversary-peko!
ありがとぺこだよ！
Thank you-peko!
なんかまた一緒に歌える機会があったら歌いたいぺこですね！
I'd like to sing together again if there's another chance-peko!
歌おう、歌おうぺこですね！
Let's sing, let's sing-peko!
うん！じゃ、ロボ子は次の曲に行ってみたいと思います！
Yeah! Then, I'd like to move on to the next song!
あ、行ってらっしゃい！頑張ってぺこ！
Ah, have a good one! Good luck-peko!
ありがとぺこら！バイバイ！また遊ぶぞ！うん！
Thanks Pekora! Bye bye! Let's play again! Yeah!
No.1 / 作詞：Gom, shito 作曲：shito
No.1 / Lyrics: Gom, shito Composition: shito
ごめん、憧れてた
Sorry, I was longing for it
追いかけてた
I was chasing after it
いつまでもそばでいたかった
I wanted to be by your side forever
完璧なあなた
The perfect you
嫌になった
I've come to hate it
同じように愛もらって
Even though I received the same love
育ったのに
And grew up
いつからか差が開いてた
At some point, a gap opened up
八つ当たりだってしたかった
I even wanted to take it out on you
ねぇねぇねぇ神様は試練与えた
Hey, hey, hey, God gave us a trial
「強くなれよ」と
Telling us to 'become stronger'
うざい
How annoying
平等なんて嘘つき
Equality is a lie
わかってるけど
I know that, but...
勝ちたいとか泣きたいとか
I want to win, I want to cry
諦めないの女の子だし
I won't give up, since I'm a girl
しおらしく猫かぶり
Meekly playing innocent
うー No.1よ／愛してね
Ooh, I'm No.1 / Please love me
生き方は無限にある
There are infinite ways to live
お父様の大袈裟な言葉
My father's exaggerated words
いじらしく猫かぶり
Lovably playing innocent
私らしくいこう
Let's go my own way
暇じゃない人生／生きよう
A life that isn't boring / Let's live
さて 理想いえば きりがなくて
Now, if I talk about ideals, there's no end...
ないもの全部欲しがって
...wanting everything I don't have.
鏡を見たって ため息 はぁ
Even when I look in the mirror, I sigh, "Haa."
あなただって 悩んでいた 知らなかった
Even you were worried, I didn't know.
みんなと同じだった 知っていた?
It was the same as everyone else, did you know?
ピュアなハート糸 揺るげない自分を信じて
With a pure heartstring, believe in your unwavering self.
神様は楽しんでる 予測的な人
God is enjoying it, an unpredictable person.
私はそれ以上に 楽しんでやるぜ
I'm going to enjoy it even more than that!
勉強とか お仕事とか 諦めないの
Studies, work, I won't give up on them.
女の子だし 経験値 愛想よく
I'm a girl, experience points, being amiable.
たまにはクールに ついてきて
Sometimes I'll be cool, just follow me.
愛しか勝たん 愛されるの
Love is all that matters, being loved.
お母さんがくれたアドバイス
The advice my mom gave me.
張り切って ミスしても 私らしくいこう
Work hard, even if I make a mistake, I'll go my way.
むねはっていこう
Go with my chest out!
さらけだせば 心があたたかくなってたんだ
When I bared it all, my heart became warm.
好きでいてね 痛くない
Please keep liking me, it doesn't hurt.
神様は夢与えた 変われるために
God gave me dreams so that I could change.
サンキュー 乗っかってやるよ 最後まで付き合って もやもや
Thank you, I'll ride along, stay with me to the end, all that fog.
雨は止んで 傘は閉じた
The rain stopped, the umbrella closed.
今まで見えてなかった景色
The scenery I hadn't seen until now.
透明が反射して 世界を照らした むねおどる
Transparency reflected and illuminated the world, my heart leaps.
可愛いとか モテたいとか 諦めないの
Cute, wanting to be popular, I won't give up on those.
女の子だし おしとやかに 猫かぶり
I'm a girl, being ladylike, acting demure.
ナンバーワンでしょ 愛して見せ方は無限にある
I'm number one, right? There are infinite ways to show love.
お父さんは大袈裟な言葉
Dad's exaggerated words...
いじらしく 猫かぶり
...endearingly acting demure.
私らしくいこう 暇じゃない人生
I'll go my way. Live a life that's not bored.
生きよう
Let's live!
おー！というわけでナンバーワンでした！
Whoa! So that was "Number One"!
すごい声出たんだけどちょっと待って。
A weird voice came out, hold on a sec.
え？あ、え？みんな、え？
Eh? Oh, eh? Everyone, eh?
アイドル衣装にロボ子、なってるよこれー！
Roboco has turned into her idol costume!
え？ちょっと待ってお気づきの方おる？
Eh? Wait a minute, did anyone notice?
ロボ子なんと、他の3D衣装と同じメイクに
Roboco, surprisingly, has the same makeup
なってるんだけど！うおー！
as the other 3D outfits! Whoa!
なんとアップデートされたアイドル衣装です。
It's the updated idol costume!
どーりゃー？どーりゃー可愛いか？
How is it? How is it, is it cute?
可愛いに決まってんだよなー。
Of course it's cute.
え、マジでいきなりでびっくりした？
Eh, were you really surprised by the sudden change?
このタイミングで本当に合ってるのか？
Is this really the right timing?
うんうん、うんうん。合っています。
Yeah, yeah. It is.
はいというわけで。でもね、歌はもう終盤なんですよ。
Right. But you know, the songs are already in the final stage.
で、最後の曲はこのアップデートされた
And, I want to sing the last song
アイドル衣装で歌いたいなと思って、先に着替えてきちゃいました。
in this updated idol costume, so I changed into it beforehand.
可愛いでしょ。ちょっと今のうちにね、
It's cute, right? Please take lots of
いっぱいスクショ撮っておいてください。
screenshots while you can.
おはにゃー、可愛い。ういっく。
Ohanya, cute. *hic*.
ピース。にぱにぱにぱにぱ。
Peace. Nipa nipa nipa nipa.
はいというわけで、終盤ということは！
Alright, and since it's the final stage...
もちろん！
...of course!
うー！グッズ紹介でーす！
Woo! It's time for the goods reveal!
はい！4周年記念グッズ！もちろん出すぞー！
Yes! 4th anniversary goods! Of course I'm releasing them!
それでは運営さん出しちゃってー！
Alright, staff, bring them out!
見てください！
Look at this!
とりゃ！
Toria!
はい、というわけでロボ子さん4周年活動記念グッズ
So, here are the commemorative goods for
発表したいと思います！
Roboco's 4th anniversary activities!
それでは運営さん、1つ目を、どーん！
Now staff, let's show the first one, boom!
はい、こちらですね、tifish先生の書き下ろしの
Yes, this is the B2 tapestry
B2タペストリーとなっております！
specially drawn by tifish-sensei!
めっちゃお姉さんでめっちゃ可愛くない？
Doesn't it look like a big sister and super cute?
なのにロボコ、実はまだ5歳なので
And yet, Roboco is actually still 5 years old,
食べれるようになったプリンと
so I'm eating pudding
お子様オムライス食べてます！
and a kid's omelet rice!
どう、このギャップ！
What do you think of this gap!
5歳児のお姉さんは、いかがですか？
How do you like a 5-year-old big sister?
可愛いでしょう、これ。めちゃめちゃ可愛いよね。
It's cute, isn't it? It's super cute.
みんなも欲しくなっちゃったんじゃないの？どうよ？
Don't you all want it now? How about it?
あれ、ねぇ...
Wait, hey...
スプーンとフォーク、ちょっと...
The spoon and fork, wait...
あれ？なんかそれまでロボ子のモチーフになってるの
Oh? Even those have Roboco's motifs on them.
気づいちゃった人いるかな？
I wonder if anyone noticed?
運営さん、ちょっと次も見せてくださいよ！
Staff, please show the next one!
次！
Next!
あーそうなんです！
Ah, that's right!
なんとこちらですね、ロボ子が描きました！こっち！
Believe it or not, I drew these myself! These!
なんとこれロボ子が描きました！どう？可愛くない？
I drew these! What do you think? Aren't they cute?
そう、ロボ子が描いたロボさー（リボンバージョン）と
Yeah, the Robosa (ribbon version) I drew and...
ロボコ、ツノおさげバージョンとなっております！
Roboco, horn-braids version!
なんとね、初めてのカトラリーセットというわけでね
It's my first ever cutlery set,
さっきのタペストリーにも混ざってました！うん！
and it was also in the tapestry earlier! Yeah!
カトラリー、カトラリー
Cutlery, cutlery...
間違え...「カラトリ」って言ったのバカなんじゃないの？
I messed up... Whoever said "Karatori" is an idiot, right?
誰、誰か知らんけど。
Whoever it was, I don't know who.
うえ、ロボコ噛んでないもん！
Ugh, Roboco didn't stutter!
噛んでないもん！
I didn't stutter!
カトラリー。こちらカトラリーですね。
Cutlery. These are cutlery.
え、噛んでないので、買ってください！
Um, I didn't stutter, so please buy them!
これで食べたら高性能に間違いなし！
Eating with these will definitely make you high-performance!
買ってよね、うん。
Buy them, okay?
ロボコはこれでご飯を食べます。
Roboco will eat her meals with these.
はい、2つぐらい買っておくとね、おすすめですよ！
Yes, I recommend buying two sets!
洗うのがね、一気にいっぱい使えるので。うん、うん、うん。
Since you can use a bunch at once before washing them. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
さあ、そしてですね、まだあるんですよ！
Well, and there's more!
それではこちらを、どーん！
So here's this, boom!
はい、そう、なんとランチプレート付き！
Yes, believe it or not, it comes with a lunch plate!
どうこれ！ロボコなんか結構こういうお皿が好きでさ
What do you think! I really like this kind of plate,
いつも普段使いしてるんだけど
and I use them all the time,
やっぱさ、オリジナルバージョン欲しくなっちゃったから
but I really wanted an original version,
今回作ってみました！
so I made one this time!
私利私欲！
Self-interest!
もうほんまに今回私利私欲かもしんないけど
This time might really be out of self-interest,
でもみんなご飯作りたいよね！
but everyone wants to cook meals, right!
ロボコと一緒にご飯食べたいよね！
You want to eat with Roboco, right!
じゃあもうお皿もフォークもスプーンもロボコとお揃いにしちゃおう！
Then let's make the plate, fork, and spoon match Roboco's!
そういうことですよ！
That's what I'm talking about!
これでロボコと同じ料理間違いなし！
With this, it'll definitely be the same meal as Roboco!
一緒に料理しようね！
Let's cook together!
さあ、そしてこちらのね、イラストが描いてあるんですけど
And, there's an illustration on here,
こちらのイラストもなんと、こちらにも出てきます！
and this illustration also appears here!
うっとりゃ！
U-toria!
はい！というわけでですね、こちらはアクリルキーホルダー！
Yes! So, these are acrylic keychains!
こちらランダムの4種類となっております！
There are 4 random types!
はい、もうめっちゃポン！ちょっとポンなりかけ、
Yes, "super-pon", "almost-pon",
え、可愛い、可愛いの4種類となっております！
and "cute", "cute" are the four types!
どうですか？こちらはですね、アカババ先生がね、
What do you think? These are random keychains
書き下ろしてくれたランダムキーホルダーとなっております！
specially drawn by Akababa-sensei!
アクリルキーホルダーですね。
Acrylic keychains.
え、どれも可愛いでしょう！
Um, they're all cute, right!
でも個人的には、は、は、は、ボーンが好き！
But personally, I like the "boom" one!
もうボーンが好き！
I love the "boom" one!
めっちゃ可愛くないこのアフロ？
Isn't this afro super cute?
やっぱアフロいいよな！
Afros are great, after all!
そう、こちらですね、ランダムでありますので、
Yes, these are random, so
皆さんぜひ全種類ゲット目指して頑張ってみてください！
please aim to get all types!
まあ同じのいっぱいあっても可愛いなって思っちゃうロボコなんですけどね。うん！
Well, I think having many of the same one is also cute. Yeah!
はい、というわけで、今回も活動4周年記念フルセット、
Yes, and so, the 4th anniversary activity full set
数量限定版は、今言った全部！
limited edition includes everything I just mentioned!
そして、tifish先生のロボコお姉さん風の
And, the tapestry of
お子様ランチ食べてるあのタペストリーの、
Roboco like an older sister eating a kid's lunch
え、ポストカードに、直筆サイン、
by tifish-sensei, as a postcard with a handwritten signature
そして複製箔押しメッセージ入りが入ってるやつが、
and a duplicated foil-stamped message,
購入特典となっております！
is the purchase benefit!
言えなかった...
I couldn't say it...
えー、導入されております！ドーン！
Uh, it's being introduced! Ta-da!
可愛いですよ、これ。ポストカード。
These are cute. The postcards.
というわけでね、こちら数量限定なので、みんなゲットしてくれよな。
So, these are limited quantity, so everyone, please get them.
今のうちに待機しとくん段ぞ。
Be on standby for now.
このあとですからね。はい。
It's coming up next. Yes.
うるせー、ポンじゃなーい！
Shut up, I'm not clumsy!
ポンは... ポンは日常だ。
Being clumsy is... It's just a daily thing.
ポンは日常だから。もう、諦める、ロボ子。
It's just a part of daily life. I give up, Roboco.
ポンと一緒に生きるんだ。
I'll live with being clumsy.
はい、というわけでね、まあもちろん数量限定版買えなくても...
Yes, so, even if you can't buy the limited edition...
ポストカードね、えー、ロボ子のね、サイン入り複製バージョンのね、やつ、ありますので。
There are postcards with a reproduction of my signature.
メッセージ入りが。ぜひそっちのね...
With a message included. Please, those...
フルセットも購入してください！はい！
Purchase the full set as well! Yes!
というわけで、いかがでしたか？
So, how was it?
今日はなんか、4周年だったけど、ポンっちゃったような気がしなくもないんですけど。
Today was the 4th anniversary, but I feel like I might've been a bit clumsy.
はあ〜... 大丈夫だよね？うん。
Sigh... It's okay, right? Yeah.
まあでも、最後はきっちり決めたいと思いますので。
But, I want to finish it off properly at the end.
ロボ子の最後の曲、聴いてください。
Please listen to Roboco's last song.
このアイドル衣装にちなんだアイドル曲を歌わせていただきます。
I will sing an idol song that fits this idol outfit.
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
誇り高きアイドル
Proud Idol
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is
上手く歌えてますか？
Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
My outfit, my makeup
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
振り付けとかあざとさも
The choreography and the coy cuteness
喜んでもらえますか？
Do you enjoy them?
手は冷たくなって
My hands get cold
足は震える
My legs shake
それでも戦いたい
Even so, I want to fight
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of me
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon too
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Words like "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say them when you haven't even looked
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't say effort is a given
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force images on me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The words "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
Are what I hate most in this world
プライベート見えないから
You can't see my private life
分からないと思います
So I don't think you know
性格とか悪いほうです
My personality is on the bad side
騙しちゃっていますか？
Am I deceiving you?
でも本気です本気なんです
But I'm serious, I really am
ありのままの私を
The way I am
好きになって愛してください
Please like and love me
それってわがままですか？
Is that being selfish?
きっと可愛くない
I'm surely not cute
全部分かってる
I know everything
それでも好かれてたい
Even so, I want to be liked
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who say cynical things
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate constant excuses too
「こんなもんか」という言葉を
Words like "is this all?"
軽々しく口にするな
Don't speak so lightly
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't decide limits on your own
笑い者にだってするな
Don't make a laughingstock either
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The words "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
Are what I hate most in this world
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwind
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it
お金がなければ活動できない
Can't continue activities without money
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
Can't survive on just things you like
感謝してるはずが
Should be grateful
もらってばかりだし
But I'm only receiving
恩返しできる日まで
Until the day I can repay the favor
待ってて
Please wait
歓声が減っても
Even if the cheers decrease
飽きられちゃっても
Even if people get bored of me
それでも笑っていたい
Even so, I want to be smiling
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
熱いファンの愛があって
There is the love of passionate fans...
With the love of my passionate fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
With the love of the staff members,
いつも家族の愛があって
With the love of my family always,
生きてる
I am alive.
“アイドル”
"Idol"
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of us.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon, too.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The words "just an idol,"
見てもいないくせに言うな
don't say them when you haven't even seen us.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't say our hard work is to be expected.
イメージとか強要するな
Don't force your expectations on us.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The words "just an idol,"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
I hate them most of all in this world!
-出演-
- Cast -
ロボ子さん
Roboco-san
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna